<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string name="app_name">PPIJ</string>
    <string name="hello_world">Hello world!</string>
    <string name="action_settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="learn">Learn</string>
    <string name="quiz">Quiz</string>
    <string name="gallery">Gallery</string>
    <string name="title_activity_learn_screen">LearnScreen</string>
    <string name="title_activity_quiz_screen">QuizScreen</string>
    <string name="title_activity_gallery_screen">GalleryScreen</string>
    <string name="title_activity_slider_game">SliderGameActivity</string>
    <string name="Play_Game">Play Game</string>
    <string name="title_activity_mastermind">MastermindActivity</string>
    <string name="title_activity_show_picture_ar">showPictureAR</string>
    <string name="title_activity_find_differences_game">findDifferencesGame</string>
    <string name="title_activity_theory_menu">TheoryMenuActivity</string>
    <string name="title_activity_memory_activity">MemoryActivity</string>
    <string name="title_activity_color_picker">ColorPickerActivity</string>
    <string name="title_activity_grid_game">GridGameActivity</string>


    <string name="theory_1_0">The Renaissance  is a period from the 14th to the 17th century, considered the bridge between theMiddle Ages and modern history. It started as a cultural movement in Italy in the Late Medieval period and later spread to the rest of Europe. \n\t The word Renaissance, literally meaning \"Rebirth\" in French, first appears in English in the 1830s. The word occurs in Jules Michelet\'s 1855 work, Histoire de France. \n\t The Renaissance marks the period of European history at the close of the Middle Ages and the rise of the Modern world. It represents a cultural rebirth from the 14th through the middle of the 17th centuries. Early Renaissance, mostly in Italy, bridges the art period during the fifteenth century, between the Middle Ages and the High Renaissance in Italy. It is generally known that Renaissance matured in Northern Europe later, in the 16th century. One of the distinguishing features of Renaissance art was its development of highly realistic linear perspective. Giotto di Bondone (1267–1337) is credited with first treating a painting as a window into space. \n\t The development of perspective was part of a wider trend towards realism in the arts. To that end, painters also developed other techniques, studying light, shadow, and, famously in the case of Leonardo da Vinci, human anatomy. Underlying these changes in artistic method, was a renewed desire to depict the beauty of nature, and to unravel the axioms of aesthetics, with the works of Leonardo, Michelangelo and Raphael representing artistic pinnacles that were to be much imitated by other artists. \n\t Many works of Renaissance art depicted religious images, including subjects such as the Virgin Mary, or Madonna, and were encountered by contemporary audiences of the period in the context of religious rituals. Today, they are viewed as great works of art, but at the time they were seen and used mostly as devotional objects. Many Renaissance works were painted as altarpieces for incorporation into rituals associated with Catholic Mass and donated by patrons who sponsored the Mass itself.</string>
    <string name="title_1_0">The Renaissance</string>

    <string name="theory_1_1">Leonardo di ser Piero da Vinci (15 April 1452 – 2 May 1519) was an Italian polymath, painter, sculptor, architect, musician, mathematician, engineer, inventor, anatomist, geologist, cartographer, botanist, and writer. He is widely considered to be one of the greatest painters of all time and perhaps the most diversely talented person ever to have lived. His genius, perhaps more than that of any other figure, epitomized the Renaissance humanist ideal. Leonardo has often been described as the archetype of the Renaissance Man, a man of \"unquenchable curiosity\" and \"feverishly inventive imagination\".\n\t Leonardo was, and is, renowned primarily as a painter. Among his works, the Mona Lisa is the most famous and most parodied portrait and The Last Supper the most reproduced religious painting of all time, with their fame approached only by Michelangelo\'s The Creation of Adam. Leonardo\'s drawing of the Vitruvian Man is also regarded as a cultural icon, being reproduced on items as varied as the euro coin, textbooks, and T-shirts. Perhaps fifteen of his paintings have survived, the small number because of his constant, and frequently disastrous, experimentation with new techniques. Nevertheless, these few works, together with his notebooks, which contain drawings, scientific diagrams, and his thoughts on the nature of painting, compose a contribution to later generations of artists rivalled only by that of his contemporary, Michelangelo. \n\tLeonardo is revered for his technological ingenuity. He conceptualised flying machines, an armoured vehicle, concentrated solar power, an adding machine, and the double hull, also outlining a rudimentary theory of plate tectonics. He made substantial discoveries in anatomy, civil engineering, optics, and hydrodynamics, but he did not publish his findings and they had no direct influence on later science.</string>
    <string name="title_1_1">Leonardo da Vinci</string>

    <string name="theory_1_2">The Mona Lisa is a half-length portrait of a woman by the Italian artist Leonardo da Vinci, which has been acclaimed as \"the best known, the most visited, the most written about, the most sung about, the most parodied work of art in the world\".\n\tThe title of the painting, which is known in English as Mona Lisa, comes from a description by Renaissance art historian Giorgio Vasari, who wrote \"Leonardo undertook to paint, for Francesco del Giocondo, the portrait of Mona Lisa, his wife.\" Mona in Italian is a polite form of address originating as ma donna – similar to Ma’am, Madam, or my lady in English. This became madonna, and its contraction mona.  \n\tLeonardo da Vinci began painting the Mona Lisa in 1503 or 1504 in Florence, Italy. In 1516, Leonardo was invited by King François I to work at the Clos Lucé near the king\'s castle in Amboise. It is believed that he took the Mona Lisa with him and continued to work after he moved to France. Art historian Carmen C. Bambach has concluded that da Vinci probably continued refining the work until 1516 or 1517. On his death the painting was inherited, among other works, by his pupil and assistant Salaì. The king bought the painting for 4,000 écus and kept it at Palace of Fontainebleau. After the French Revolution, it was moved to the Louvre where it is now on permanent display.\n\t The painting was among the first portraits to depict the sitter before an imaginary landscape and Leonardo was one of the first painters to use aerial perspective. Leonardo used a pyramid design to place the woman simply and calmly in the space of the painting. Her folded hands form the front corner of the pyramid. Her breast, neck and face glow in the same light that models her hands. The light gives the variety of living surfaces an underlying geometry of spheres and circles. Leonardo referred to a seemingly simple formula for seated female figure: the images of seated Madonna, which were widespread at the time. He effectively modified this formula in order to create the visual impression of distance between the sitter and the observer.</string>
    <string name="title_1_2">Mona Lisa</string>

    <string name="theory_1_3">The Last Supper  is a late 15th-century mural painting by Leonardo da Vinci in the refectory of the Convent of Santa Maria delle Grazie, Milan. It is one of the world\'s most famous paintings, and one of the most studied, scrutinized, and satirized.\n\tThe work is presumed to have been commenced around 1495 and was commissioned as part of a plan of renovations to the church and its convent buildings by Leonardo\'s patron Ludovico Sforza, Duke of Milan. The painting represents the scene of The Last Supper of Jesus with his disciples, as it is told in the Gospel of John, 13:21. Leonardo has depicted the consternation that occurred among the Twelve Disciples when Jesus announced that one of them would betray him.\n\tThe Last Supper specifically portrays the reaction given by each apostle when Jesus said one of them would betray him. All twelve apostles have different reactions to the news, with various degrees of anger and shock. The apostles are identified from a manuscript (The Notebooks of Leonardo da Vinci p. 232) with their names found in the 19th century. (Before this, only Judas, Peter, John and Jesus were positively identified.)</string>
    <string name="title_1_3">The Last Supper</string>

    <string name="theory_1_4">Michelangelo di Lodovico Buonarroti Simoni (6 March 1475 – 18 February 1564), commonly known as Michelangelo, was an Italian sculptor, painter, architect, poet, and engineer of the High Renaissance who exerted an unparalleled influence on the development of Western art. Considered as the greatest living artist in his lifetime, he has since been held as one of the greatest artists of all time. Despite making few forays beyond the arts, his versatility in the disciplines he took up was of such a high order that he is often considered a contender for the title of the archetypal Renaissance man, along with his fellow Italian Leonardo da Vinci.\n\tA number of his works in painting, sculpture, and architecture rank among the most famous in existence. His output in every field during his long life was prodigious; when the sheer volume of correspondence, sketches, and reminiscences that survive is also taken into account, he is the best-documented artist of the 16th century.\n\tTwo of his best-known works, the Pietà and David, were sculpted before he turned thirty. Despite his low opinion of painting, Michelangelo also created two of the most influential works in fresco in the history of Western art: the scenes from Genesis on the ceiling and The Last Judgment on the altar wall of the Sistine Chapel in Rome. In a demonstration of Michelangelo\'s unique standing, he was the first Western artist whose biography was published while he was alive.\n\tMichelangelo, with Leonardo da Vinci and Raphael, is one of the three giants of the Florentine High Renaissance. Although their names are often cited together, Michelangelo was younger than Leonardo by 23 years, and older than Raphael by eight. Because of his reclusive nature, he had little to do with either artist and outlived both of them by more than forty years. Michelangelo took few sculpture students.\n\tArtists who were directly influenced by Michelangelo include Raphael, who imitated Michelangelo\'s prophets in two of his works, including his depiction of the great master in the School of Athens. Other artists, such as Pontormo, drew on the writhing forms of the Last Judgement and the frescoes of the Capella Paolina.</string>
    <string name="title_1_4">Michelangelo</string>

    <string name="theory_1_5">The Sistine Chapel ceiling, painted by Michelangelo between 1508 and 1512, is a cornerstone work of High Renaissance art. The ceiling\'s various painted elements form part of a larger scheme of decoration within the Chapel, which includes the large fresco The Last Judgment on the sanctuary wall, also by Michelangelo, wall paintings by several leading painters of the late 15th century including Sandro Botticelli, Domenico Ghirlandaio and Pietro Perugino, and a set of large tapestries by Raphael, the whole illustrating much of the doctrine of the Catholic Church.\n\tCentral to the ceiling decoration are nine scenes from the Book of Genesis of which The Creation of Adam is the best known, having an iconic standing equalled only by Leonardo da Vinci\'s Mona Lisa, the hands of God and Adam being reproduced in countless imitations. The complex design includes several sets of individual figures, both clothed and nude, which allowed Michelangelo to fully demonstrate his skill in creating a huge variety of poses for the human figure, and have provided an enormously influential pattern book of models for other artists ever since. \n\tThe narrative elements of the ceiling illustrate that God made the World as a perfect creation and put humanity into it, that humanity fell into disgrace and was punished by death and by separation from God. Humanity then sank further into sin and disgrace, and was punished by the Great Flood. Through a lineage of Ancestors – from Abraham to Joseph – God sent the saviour of humanity, Christ Jesus. The coming of the Saviour was prophesied by Prophets of Israel and Sibyls of the Classical world. The various components of the ceiling are linked to this Christian doctrine. Traditionally, the Old Testament was perceived as a prefiguring of the New Testament. Many incidents and characters of the Old Testament were commonly understood as having a direct symbolic link to some particular aspect of the life of Jesus or to an important element of Christian doctrine or to a sacrament such as Baptism or the Eucharist. Jonah, for example was readily recognisable by his attribute of the large fish, and was commonly seen to symbolised Jesus\' death and resurrection.</string>
    <string name="title_1_5">Ceiling of Sistine Chapel</string>

    <string name="theory_1_6">David is a masterpiece of Renaissance sculpture created between 1501 and 1504, by Michelangelo.\n\tIt is a 4.34-metre, 5.17-metre with the base marble statue of a standing male nude. The statue represents the Biblical hero David, a favoured subject in the art of Florence.Originally commissioned as one of a series of statues of prophets to be positioned along the roofline of the east end of Florence Cathedral, the statue was placed instead in a public square, outside the Palazzo della Signoria, the seat of civic government in Florence, where it was unveiled on 8 September 1504.\n\tBecause of the nature of the hero it represented, the statue soon came to symbolize the defense of civil liberties embodied in the Republic of Florence, an independent city-state threatened on all sides by more powerful rival states and by the hegemony of the Medici family. The eyes of David, with a warning glare, were turned towards Rome.\n\tThe statue appears to show David after he has made the decision to fight Goliath but before the battle has actually taken place, a moment between conscious choice and action. The statue is a Renaissance interpretation of a common ancient Greek theme of the standing heroic male nude. In the High Renaissance, contrapposto poses were thought of as a distinctive feature of antique sculpture. This is typified in David, as the figure stands with one leg holding its full weight and the other leg forward. This classic pose causes the figure’s hips and shoulders to rest at opposing angles, giving a slight s-curve to the entire torso. The contrapposto is emphasised by the turn of the head to the left, and by the contrasting positions of the arms. Michelangelo’s David has become one of the most recognized works of Renaissance sculpture, a symbol of strength and youthful beauty. It was the colossal size of the statue that impressed most of Michelangelo\'s contemporaries, however. some described it as \"certainly a miracle that of Michelangelo, to restore to life one who was dead,\".</string>
    <string name="title_1_6">David</string>

    <string name="theory_1_7">Raffaello Sanzio da Urbino(April 6 or March 28, 1483 – April 6, 1520), known as Raphael, was an Italian painter and architect of the High Renaissance. His work is admired for its clarity of form, ease of composition, and visual achievement of the Neoplatonic ideal of human grandeur. Together with Michelangelo and Leonardo da Vinci, he forms the traditional trinity of great masters of that period. Raphael was enormously productive, running an unusually large workshop and, despite his death at 37, leaving a large body of work.\n\tThe best known work is The School of Athens in the Vatican Stanza della Segnatura. After his early years in Rome much of his work was executed by his workshop from his drawings, with considerable loss of quality. He was extremely influential in his lifetime, though outside Rome his work was mostly known from his collaborative printmaking. After his death, the influence of his great rival Michelangelo was more widespread until the 18th and 19th centuries, when Raphael\'s more serene and harmonious qualities were again regarded as the highest models.\n\tRaphael was highly admired by his contemporaries, although his influence on artistic style in his own century was less than that of Michelangelo. Mannerism, beginning at the time of his death, and later the Baroque, took art \"in a direction totally opposed\" to Raphael\'s qualities \"with Raphael\'s death, classic art – the High Renaissance – subsided.\n\tRaphael was one of the finest draftsmen in the history of Western art, and used drawings extensively to plan his compositions. According to a near-contemporary, when beginning to plan a composition, he would lay out a large number of stock drawings of his on the floor, and begin to draw \"rapidly\", borrowing figures from here and there. This is how Raphael himself, who was so rich in inventiveness, used to work, always coming up with four or six ways to show a narrative, each one different from the rest, and all of them full of grace and well done.</string>
    <string name="title_1_7">Raphael</string>

    <string name="theory_1_8">The School of Athens, or Scuola di Atene in Italian, is one of the most famous frescoes by the Italian Renaissance artist Raphael. It was painted between 1509 and 1511 as a part of Raphael\'s commission to decorate the rooms now known as the Stanze di Raffaello, in the Apostolic Palace in the Vatican. The picture has long been seen as \"Raphael\'s masterpiece and the perfect embodiment of the classical spirit of the Renaissance.\n\tThe School of Athens represents all the greatest mathematicians, philosophers and scientists from classical antiquity gathered together sharing their ideas and learning from each other. These figures all lived at different times, but here they are gathered together under one roof. The identities of some of the philosophers in the picture, such as Plato or Aristotle, are certain. Beyond that, identifications of Raphael’s figures have always been hypothetical. Those who can be identified with some certainty are Plato, Aristotle, Socrates, Pythagoras, Euclid, Ptolemy, Zoroaster, Raphael, Sodoma and Diogenes. Other identifications are more or less speculative.\n\tIn the center of the fresco, at its architecture\'s central vanishing point, are the two undisputed main subjects: Plato on the left and Aristotle, his student, on the right. Both figures hold modern (of the time), bound copies of their books in their left hands, while gesturing with their right. Plato holds Timaeus, Aristotle his Nicomachean Ethics. Plato is depicted as old, grey, wise-looking, and bare-foot. By contrast Aristotle, slightly ahead of him, is in mature manhood, handsome, well-shod and dressed with gold, and the youth about them seem to look his way. Plato points up and Aristotle holds his hand down. It is popularly thought that their gestures indicate central aspects of their philosophies and divergence of the two philosophical schools. Plato argues a sense of timelessness whilst Aristotle looks into the physicality of life and the present realm.</string>
    <string name="title_1_8">School of Athens</string>

    <string name="theory_1_9">Sistine Madonna, also called La Madonna di San Sisto, is an oil painting by the Italian artist Raphael. Commissioned in 1512 by Pope Julius II as an altarpiece for the church of San Sisto, Piacenza, it was one of the last Madonnas painted by the artist. Relocated to Dresden from 1754, the well-known painting has been particularly influential in Germany. After World War II, it was relocated to Moscow for a decade before it was returned to Germany. There, it resides as one of the central pieces in the Gemäldegalerie Alte Meister. In the painting the Madonna, holding the Christ Child and flanked by Saint Sixtus and Saint Barbara, stands on clouds before dozens of obscured cherubs, while two distinctive winged cherubs rest on their elbows beneath her.\n\tOne of the artist\'s last Madonnas, the painting was commissioned by Pope Julius II in 1512 in honor of his late uncle, Pope Sixtus IV, as an altarpiece for the Benedictine basilica of the Monastery of San Sisto, Piacenza, a church with which the Rovere family had a long-standing relationship. It was their requirement that the image contain both Saint Sixtus and Saint Barbara. Legend has it that when Antonio da Correggio first laid eyes on the piece, he was inspired to cry, \"And I also, I am a painter!\"\n\tA prominent element within the painting, the winged angels beneath Mary are famous in their own right. As early as 1913 famous critics declared that \"no cherub or group of cherubs is so famous as the two that lean on the altar top indicated at the very bottom of the picture.\" Heavily marketed, they have been featured in stamps, postcards, T-shirts, and wrapping paper. These cherubim have inspired legends of their own. According to a 1912 article in Fra Magazine, when Raphael was painting the Madonna the children of his model would come in to watch. Struck by their posture as they did, the story goes, he added them to the painting exactly as he saw them. Another story, recounted in 1912\'s St. Nicholas Magazine, says that Raphael rather was inspired by two children he encountered on the street when he saw them \"looking wistfully into the window of a baker\'s shop.\" prompting the neologism Sitonna.</string>
    <string name="title_1_9">Sistine Madonna</string>

    <string name="theory_1_10">Tiziano Vecelli or Tiziano Vecellio , known in English as Titian, was an Italian painter, the most important member of the 16th-century Venetian school.\n\tRecognized by his contemporaries as \"The Sun Amidst Small Stars\", Titian was one of the most versatile of Italian painters, equally adept with portraits, landscape backgrounds, and mythological and religious subjects. His painting methods, particularly in the application and use of color, would exercise a profound influence not only on painters of the Italian Renaissance, but on future generations of Western art.\n\tDuring the course of his long life, Titian\'s artistic manner changed drastically but he retained a lifelong interest in color. Although his mature works may not contain the vivid, luminous tints of his early pieces, their loose brushwork and subtlety of tone are without precedent in the history of Western painting. He was noted for his mastery of colour.</string>
    <string name="title_1_10">Titian</string>

    <string name="theory_1_11">Assumption of the Virgin is a large oil painting by Italian Renaissance artist Titian, executed in 1516–1518. It is located on the high altar in the Basilica di Santa Maria Gloriosa dei Frari in Venice, being the largest altarpiece in the city.\n\tThe Assumption of the Virgin was Titian\'s first major commission in Venice. He soon became the lead painter of Venice. Breaking tradition with its heroic character scale and trademark color, its twisted Virgin and dramatically gesturing apostles disturbed passersby. When Titian placed this giant painting in its majestic marble frame, it garnered much attention. It was deemed worth noting by the Venetian diarist, Marino Sanuto the Younger, who wrote, \"May 20, 1518: Yesterday the panel painted by Titian for … the Minorites was put up.\n\tThe Assumption of the virgin depicted in the painting is celebrated every year on August 15 and is a defined dogma of the Catholic church. It commemorates the rising of Mary to heaven before the decay of her body. It is a sign of her passing into eternal life and thus, it is a holy day of obligation. There is a distinction between the ascension of Jesus and the assumption of Mary. The ascension was the rising of Jesus under his own power, while the assumption means that someone else raised Mary to heaven. It is said that Jesus himself came and carried her up. This picture shows different events in three layers. In the lowest layer are the Apostles. They are shown in a variety of poses, ranging from gazing in awe, to kneeling and reaching for the skies. In the center, the Virgin Mary is drawn wrapped in a red robe and blue mantle. She is raised to the heavens by a swarm of cherubim while standing on a cloud. Above is an attempt to draw God, who watches over the earth with hair flying in the wind. Next to him, flies an angel with a crown for Mary.</string>
    <string name="title_1_11">Assumption of the Virgin</string>

    <string name="theory_1_12">The Birth of Venus (Italian: Nascita di Venere) is a painting by Sandro Botticelli generally thought to have been painted in the mid 1480s. The iconography of Birth of Venus is similar to a description of the event (or rather, a description of a sculpture of the event) in a poem by Angelo Poliziano, the Stanze per la giostra. However, no single text provides the precise imagery of the painting.\n\tFor Plato – and so for the members of the Florentine Platonic Academy – Venus had two aspects: she was an earthly goddess who aroused humans to physical love or she was a heavenly goddess who inspired intellectual love in them. Plato further argued that contemplation of physical beauty allowed the mind to better understand spiritual beauty. So, looking at Venus, the most beautiful of goddesses, might at first raise a physical response in viewers which then lifted their minds towards the godly. A Neoplatonic reading of Botticelli\'s Birth of Venus suggests that 15th-century viewers would have looked at the painting and felt their minds lifted to the realm of divine love.</string>
    <string name="title_1_12">The Birth of Venus</string>

    <string name="theory_3_0">Impressionism is a 19th-century art movement. Impressionist painting characteristics include relatively small, thin, yet visible brush strokes, open composition, emphasis on accurate depiction of light in its changing qualities (often accentuating the effects of the passage of time), ordinary subject matter, inclusion of movement as a crucial element of human perception and experience, and unusual visual angles.\n\tIt originated with a group of Paris-based artists. Their independent exhibitions brought them to prominence during the 1870s and 1880s, in spite of harsh opposition from the conventional art community in France. The name of the style derives from the title of a Claude Monet work, Impression, soleil levant (Impression, Sunrise).\n\tRadicals in their time, early Impressionists violated the rules of academic painting. They constructed their pictures from freely brushed colours that took precedence over lines and contours.\n\tThey also painted realistic scenes of modern life, and often painted outdoors. Previously, still lifes and portraits as well as landscapes were usually painted in a studio.[1] The Impressionists found that they could capture the momentary and transient effects of sunlight by painting en plein air. They portrayed overall visual effects instead of details, and used short \"broken\" brush strokes of mixed and pure unmixed colour—not blended smoothly or shaded, as was customary—to achieve an effect of intense colour vibration.\n\tImpressionism emerged in France at the same time that a number of other painters, including the Italian artists known as the Macchiaioli, and Winslow Homer in the United States, were also exploring plein-air painting. The Impressionists, however, developed new techniques specific to the style. Encompassing what its adherents argued was a different way of seeing, it is an art of immediacy and movement, of candid poses and compositions, of the play of light expressed in a bright and varied use of colour.\n\tThe public, at first hostile, gradually came to believe that the Impressionists had captured a fresh and original vision, even if the art critics and art establishment disapproved of the new style.\n\tBy recreating the sensation in the eye that views the subject, rather than delineating the details of the subject, and by creating a welter of techniques and forms, Impressionism is a precursor of various painting styles, including Neo-Impressionism, Post-Impressionism, Fauvism, and Cubism.</string>
    <string name="title_3_0">Overview</string>

    <string name="theory_3_1">Oscar-Claude Monet  14 November 1840 – 5 December 1926) was a founder of French Impressionist painting, and the most consistent and prolific practitioner of the movement\'s philosophy of expressing one\'s perceptions before nature, especially as applied to plein-air landscape painting. The term \"Impressionism\" is derived from the title of his painting Impression, soleil levant (Impression, Sunrise), which was exhibited in 1874 in the first of the independent exhibitions mounted by Monet and his associates as an alternative to the Salon de Paris.\n\tMonet\'s ambition of documenting the French countryside led him to adopt a method of painting the same scene many times in order to capture the changing of light and the passing of the seasons. From 1883 Monet lived in Giverny, where he purchased a house and property, and began a vast landscaping project which included lily ponds that would become the subjects of his best-known works. In 1899 he began painting the water lilies, first in vertical views with a Japanese bridge as a central feature, and later in the series of large-scale paintings that was to occupy him continuously for the next 20 years of his life.\n\tMonet has been described as \"the driving force behind Impressionism\". Crucial to the art of the Impressionist painters was the understanding of the effects of light on the local colour of objects, and the effects of the juxtaposition of colours with each other. Monet\'s long career as a painter was spent in the pursuit of this aim.\n\tIn 1856, his chance meeting with Eugene Boudin, a painter of small beach scenes, opened his eyes to the possibility of plein-air painting. From that time, with a short interruption for military service, he dedicated himself to searching for new and improved methods of painterly expression. To this end, as a young man, he visited the Paris Salon and familiarised himself with the works of older painters, and made friends with other young artists.\n\t His first series exhibited as such was of Haystacks, painted from different points of view and at different times of the day. Fifteen of the paintings were exhibited at the Galerie Durand-Ruel in 1891. In 1892 he produced what is probably his best-known series, twenty-six views of Rouen Cathedral. In these paintings Monet broke with painterly traditions by cropping the subject so that only a portion of the facade is seen on the canvas. The paintings do not focus on the grand Medieval building, but on the play of light and shade across its surface, transforming the solid masonry. To this day critics praise him with comments such as this one: \"Monet, with a scientific precision, has given us an unparalleled and unexcelled record of the passing of time as seen in the movement of light over identical forms.\"</string>
    <string name="title_3_1">Oscar-Claude Monet</string>

    <string name="theory_3_2">Haystacks is a title of a series of impressionist paintings by Claude Monet. The primary subjects of all of the paintings in the series are stacks of hay in the field after the harvest season. The title refers primarily to a twenty-five canvas series begun in the end of summer of 1890 and continued through the following spring, using that year\'s harvest. Some use a broader definition of the title to refer to other paintings by Monet with this same theme. The series is known for its thematic use of repetition to show differences in perception of light across various times of day, seasons, and types of weather. The subjects were painted in fields near Monet\'s home in Giverny, France.\n\tMonet noticed this subject on a casual walk. He requested that his stepdaughter Blanche Hoschedé bring him two canvases. He believed that one canvas for overcast weather and one for sunny weather would be sufficient. However, he realized he could not demonstrate the several distinct impressions on one or two canvases. As a result, his willing helper was quickly carting as many canvases as a wheelbarrow could hold. His daily routine involved carting paints, easels, and many unfinished canvases and working on whichever canvas most closely resembled the scene of the moment as conditions fluctuated. Although he began painting realistic depictions en plein air, he eventually revised initial effects in a studio to both generate contrast and preserve the harmony within the series.\n\tAlthough the mundane subject was constant throughout this series, the underlying theme may be seen as the transience of light. This concept enabled him to use repetition to show nuances of perception as seasons, time of day, and weather changes. The constant subject provided the basis from which comparisons could be made in changes of light across this nuanced series. The first paintings in the series were started in late September or early October 1890, and he continued producing these paintings for about seven months. These paintings made Monet the first painter to paint such a large quantity of pictures of the same subject matter differentiated by light, weather, atmosphere and perspective\n\tThis series is one of Monet\'s earliest that relied on thematic repetition to illustrate nuances in perception across natural variation such as times of day, seasons, and types of weather.</string>
    <string name="title_3_2">Haystacks</string>

    <string name="theory_3_3">Water Lilies  is a series of approximately 250 oil paintings by French Impressionist Claude Monet. The paintings depict Monet\'s flower garden at Giverny and were the main focus of Monet\'s artistic production during the last thirty years of his life. Many of the works were painted while Monet suffered from cataracts.\n\tMonet\'s career long serial motif of producing and exhibiting a series of paintings related by subject and perspective began in 1889, with at least ten paintings done at the Valley of the Creuse, which were shown at the Galerie Georges Petit.\n\tDuring the 1920s, the state of France built a pair of oval rooms at the Musée de l\'Orangerie as a permanent home for eight water lily murals by Monet. The exhibit opened to the public on 16 May 1927, a few months after Monet\'s death.[1] Sixty water lily paintings from around the world were assembled for a special exhibition at the Musée de l\'Orangerie in 1999.\n\tOn 19 June 2007, one of Monet\'s water lily paintings sold for £18.5 million at a Sotheby\'s auction in London. On 24 June 2008 another of Monet\'s water lily paintings, Le bassin aux nymphéas, sold for almost £41 million at Christie\'s in London, almost double the estimate of £18 to £24 million. Those prices just show how his painting are admired even today</string>
    <string name="title_3_3">Water Lilies</string>

    <string name="theory_3_4">Pierre-Auguste Renoir, commonly known as Auguste Renoir (25 February 1841 – 3 December 1919), was a French artist who was a leading painter in the development of the Impressionist style. As a celebrator of beauty, and especially feminine sensuality, it has been said that \"Renoir is the final representative of a tradition which runs directly from Rubens to Watteau.\"\n\tRenoir\'s paintings are notable for their vibrant light and saturated color, most often focusing on people in intimate and candid compositions. The female nude was one of his primary subjects. In characteristic Impressionist style, Renoir suggested the details of a scene through freely brushed touches of color, so that his figures softly fuse with one another and their surroundings.\n\tOne of the best known Impressionist works is Renoir\'s 1876 Dance at Le Moulin de la Galette (Bal du moulin de la Galette). The painting depicts an open-air scene, crowded with people at a popular dance garden on the Butte Montmartre close to where he lived. The works of his early maturity were typically Impressionist snapshots of real life, full of sparkling color and light. By the mid-1880s, however, he had broken with the movement to apply a more disciplined formal technique to portraits and figure paintings, particularly of women. It was a trip to Italy in 1881, when he saw works by Raphael and other Renaissance masters, that convinced him that he was on the wrong path, and for the next several years he painted in a more severe style in an attempt to return to classicism. Concentrating on his drawing and emphasizing the outlines of figures, he painted works such as The Large Bathers  during what is sometimes called his \"Ingres period\".\n\tAfter 1890 he changed direction again. To dissolve outlines, as in his earlier work, he returned to thinly brushed color. From this period onward he concentrated on monumental nudes and domestic scenes, fine examples of which are Girls at the Piano, 1892, and Grandes Baigneuses, 1887. The latter painting is the most typical and successful of Renoir\'s late, abundantly fleshed nudes.\n\tA prolific artist, he created several thousand paintings. The warm sensuality of Renoir\'s style made his paintings some of the most well-known and frequently reproduced works in the history of art. The single largest collection of his works—181 paintings in all—is at the Barnes Foundation, in Philadelphia.</string>
    <string name="title_3_4">Pierre-Auguste Renoir</string>

    <string name="theory_3_5">Bal du moulin de la Galette is an 1876 painting by French artist Pierre-Auguste Renoir. It is housed at the Musée d\'Orsay in Paris and is one of Impressionism\'s most celebrated masterpieces. The painting depicts a typical Sunday afternoon at Moulin de la Galette in the district of Montmartre in Paris. In the late 19th century, working class Parisians would dress up and spend time there dancing, drinking, and eating galettes into the evening.\n\tLike other works of Renoir\'s early maturity, Bal du moulin de la Galette is a typically Impressionist snapshot of real life. It shows a richness of form, a fluidity of brush stroke, and a flickering light.\n\tRenoir conceived his project of painting the dancing at Le Moulin de la Galette in May 1876 and its execution is described in full by his civil servant friend Georges Rivière in his memoir Renoir et ses amis.\n\tRenoir painted a smaller version of the picture with the same title. Apart from their size, the two paintings are virtually identical, although the smaller is painted in a more fluid manner than the d\'Orsay version. One is presumably a copy of the original, but it is not known which is the original. It is not even known which was the one first exhibited at the 3rd Impressionist exhibition of 1877, because although the painting was catalogued and given favourable attention by critics, its entry did not indicate the size of the painting, information that would serve to identify it.\n\tAt the time of sale, it was one of the top two most expensive artworks ever sold, together with van Gogh\'s Portrait of Dr. Gachet.</string>
    <string name="title_3_5">Bal</string>

    <string name="theory_3_6">Luncheon of the Boating Party is a painting by French impressionist Pierre-Auguste Renoir. Included in the Seventh Impressionist Exhibition in 1882, it was identified as the best painting in the show by three critics.\n\tThe painting, combining figures, still-life, and landscape in one work, depicts a group of Renoir\'s friends relaxing on a balcony at the Maison Fournaise along the Seine river in Chatou, France. The painter and art patron, Gustave Caillebotte, is seated in the lower right. Renoir\'s future wife, Aline Charigot, is in the foreground playing with a small dog. On the table is fruit and wine.\n\tThe diagonal of the railing serves to demarcate the two halves of the composition, one densely packed with figures, the other all but empty, save for the two figures of the proprietor\'s daughter Louise-Alphonsine Fournaise and her brother, Alphonse Fournaise, Jr, which are made prominent by this contrast. In this painting Renoir has captured a great deal of light. The main focus of light is coming from the large opening in the balcony, beside the large singleted man in the hat. The singlets of both men in the foreground and the table-cloth all work together to reflect this light and send it through the whole composition.\n\tAt the Seventh Impressionist Exhibition in 1882, the painting generally received praise from critics, such as \"It is fresh and free without being too bawdy,\" , \"...one of the best things Renoir has painted... . There are bits of drawing that are completely remarkable, drawing- true drawing- that is a result of the juxtaposition of hues and not of line. It is one of the most beautiful pieces that this insurrectionist art by Independent artists has produced.\" or  \"If he had learned to draw, Renoir would have a very pretty picture...\"</string>
    <string name="title_3_6">Boating Party</string>

    <string name="theory_3_7">Edgar Degas (19 July 1834 – 27 September 1917) was a French artist famous for his paintings, sculptures, prints, and drawings. He is especially identified with the subject of dance; more than half of his works depict dancers. He is regarded as one of the founders of Impressionism, although he rejected the term, preferring to be called a realist. He was a superb draftsman, and particularly masterly in depicting movement, as can be seen in his renditions of dancers, racecourse subjects and female nudes. His portraits are notable for their psychological complexity and for their portrayal of human isolation.\n\tAt the beginning of his career, he wanted to be a history painter, a calling for which he was well prepared by his rigorous academic training and close study of classic art. In his early thirties, he changed course, and by bringing the traditional methods of a history painter to bear on contemporary subject matter, he became a classical painter of modern life.\n\tDegas is often identified as an Impressionist, an understandable but insufficient description. Impressionism originated in the 1860s and 1870s and grew, in part, from the realism of such painters as Courbet and Corot. The Impressionists painted the realities of the world around them using bright, \"dazzling\" colors, concentrating primarily on the effects of light, and hoping to infuse their scenes with immediacy. They wanted to express what they saw in that exact moment.\n\tTechnically, Degas differs from the Impressionists in that he \"never adopted the Impressionist color fleck\", and he continually belittled their practice of painting en plein air.He was often as anti-impressionist as the critics who reviewed the shows. As Degas himself explained, \"no art was ever less spontaneous than mine. What I do is the result of reflection and of the study of the great masters; of inspiration, spontaneity, temperament, I know nothing.\" Nonetheless, he is described more accurately as an Impressionist than as a member of any other movement.\n\tDuring his life, public reception of Degas\'s work ranged from admiration to contempt. As a promising artist in the conventional mode, Degas had a number of paintings accepted in the Salon between 1865 and 1870. These works received praise from Pierre Puvis de Chavannes and the critic Jules-Antoine Castagnary. He soon changed his mind and joined forces with the Impressionists, however, and rejected the rigid rules, judgements, and elitism of the Salon—just as the Salon and general public initially rejected the experimentalism of the Impressionists.</string>
    <string name="title_3_7">Edgar Degas</string>

    <string name="theory_3_8">The Bellelli Family, also known as Family Portrait, is an oil painting on canvas by Edgar Degas, painted ca. 1858–1867, and housed in the Musée d\'Orsay. A masterwork of Degas\' youth, the painting is a portrait of his aunt, her husband, and their two young daughters.\n\tWhile finishing his artistic training in Italy, Degas drew and painted his aunt Laura, her husband the baron Gennaro Bellelli , and their daughters Giulia and Giovanna. Although it is not known for certain when or where Degas executed the painting, it is believed that he utilized studies done in Italy to complete the work after his return to Paris. Laura, his father\'s sister, is depicted in a dress which symbolizes mourning for her father, who had recently died and appears in the framed portrait behind her. Laura Bellelli\'s countenance is dignified and austere, her gesture connected with those of her daughters. Her husband, by contrast, appears to be separated from his family. His association with business and the outside world is implied by his position at his desk. Giulia holds a livelier pose than that of her sister Giovanna, whose restraint appears to underscore the familial tensions.\n\tViewed alongside the work of Degas\' contemporaries, the painting\'s uniqueness was due in large part to the composition, which presents a family portrait painted on the grand scale of a historical drama, and whose content has been interpreted as psychologically penetrating, with the placement of the figures suggestive of the parents\' alienation from one another, and of the divided loyalties of their children.\n\tWhen exhibited at the sale of Degas\' atelier in 1918, the picture elicited some confusion from critics; one called it \"as dull as a Flemish interior, although the dry technique is distinctive.\" Most of the reviews were positive, and with the country at war, The Bellelli Family was seen as possessing a distinctly French character, a \"modern primitive\" that bore comparison to the Avignon Pieta. Since then, biographers of Degas have acknowledged it as the masterpiece of his youth.</string>
    <string name="title_3_8">The Bellielli Family</string>

    <string name="theory_3_9">Vincent Willem van Gogh (30 March 1853 – 29 July 1890) was a major Post-Impressionist painter. He was a Dutch artist whose work had a far-reaching influence on 20th-century art. His output includes portraits, self portraits, landscapes and still lifes of cypresses, wheat fields and sunflowers. Van Gogh drew as a child but did not paint until his late twenties; he completed many of his best-known works during the last two years of his life. In just over a decade he produced more than 2,100 artworks, including 860 oil paintings and more than 1,300 watercolors, drawings, sketches and prints.\n\tVan Gogh drew and painted with watercolors while at school—only a few of these paintings survive and authorship is challenged on some of those that do. When he committed to art as an adult, he began at an elementary level, copying the Cours de dessin, a drawing course edited by Charles Bargue. Within two years he had begun to seek commissions. In spring 1882, his uncle, Cornelis Marinus, owner of a well-known gallery of contemporary art in Amsterdam, asked him for drawings of the Hague. Van Gogh\'s work did not live up to his uncle\'s expectations. Marinus offered a second commission, this time specifying the subject matter in detail, but was once again disappointed with the result. Nevertheless, Van Gogh persevered. He improved the lighting of his studio by installing variable shutters and experimented with a variety of drawing materials. For more than a year he worked on single figures – highly elaborated studies in \"Black and White\", which at the time gained him only criticism. Today, they are recognized as his first masterpieces.\n\tAfter becoming familiar with Impressionist and Neo-Impressionist techniques and theories, Van Gogh went to Arles to develop on these new possibilities. But within a short time, older ideas on art and work reappeared: ideas such as working with serial imagery on related or contrasting subject matter, which would reflect on the purposes of art. As his work progressed, he painted many Self-portraits. Already in 1884 in Nuenen he had worked on a series that was to decorate the dining room of a friend in Eindhoven. Similarly in Arles, in spring 1888 he arranged his Flowering Orchards into triptychs, began a series of figures that found its end in The Roulin Family series, and finally, when Gauguin had consented to work and live in Arles side-by-side with Van Gogh, he started to work on The Décorations for the Yellow House, which was by some accounts the most ambitious effort he ever undertook. Most of his later work is involved with elaborating on or revising its fundamental settings. In the spring of 1889, he painted another, smaller group of orchards. In an April letter to Theo, he said, \"I have 6 studies of Spring, two of them large orchards. There is little time because these effects are so short-lived.\"\n\tArt historian Albert Boime believes that Van Gogh – even in seemingly fantastical compositions like Starry Night – based his work in reality. The White House at Night, shows a house at twilight with a prominent star surrounded by a yellow halo in the sky. Astronomers at Southwest Texas State University in San Marcos calculated that the star is Venus, which was bright in the evening sky in June 1890 when Van Gogh is believed to have painted the picture.</string>
    <string name="title_3_9">Vincent van Gogh</string>

    <string name="theory_3_10">The Starry Night is an oil on canvas by the Dutch post-impressionist painter Vincent van Gogh. Painted in June, 1889, it depicts the view from the east-facing window of his asylum room at Saint-Rémy-de-Provence, just before sunrise, with the addition of an idealized village.  It is regarded as among Van Gogh\'s finest works, and one of the most recognized monuments in the history of Western culture.\n\tAlthough The Starry Night was painted during the day in Van Gogh\'s ground-floor studio, it would be inaccurate to state that the picture was painted from memory. The view has been identified as the one from his bedroom window, facing east, a view which Van Gogh painted variations of no fewer than twenty-one times, including The Starry Night.\n\tVan Gogh depicted the view at different times of day and under various weather conditions, including sunrise, moonrise, sunshine-filled days, overcast days, windy days, and one day with rain. The hospital staff did not allow Van Gogh to paint in his bedroom, but he was able to make sketches in ink or charcoal on paper, and eventually he would base newer variations on previous versions. The pictorial element uniting all of these paintings is the diagonal line coming in from the right depicting the low rolling hills of the Alpilles mountains.\n\tOne of the first paintings of the view was Mountainous Landscape Behind Saint-Rémy, now in Copenhagen, which Van Gogh identified in a letter to his sister Wil from 16 June 1889 as hanging in his studio to dry. Two days later, he wrote to his brother that he had painted \"a starry sky.\" The Starry Night is the only nocturne painting in the series of views from his bedroom window. In early June Vincent wrote to Theo, \"This morning I saw the countryside from my window a long time before sunrise with nothing but the morning star, which looked very big.\" Two scholars working independently of each other have determined that Venus was indeed visible in Provence in the spring of 1889. So the brightest \"star\" in the painting, just to the viewer\'s right of the cypress tree, is actually Venus.\n\tThe moon is stylized, as astronomical records indicate that the moon was waning gibbous at the time Van Gogh painted the picture.Even if the phase of the moon had been a waning crescent at the time, Van Gogh\'s moon is not astronomically correct.The one pictorial element that was definitely not visible from Van Gogh\'s cell is the village, which is based on a sketch made from a hillside above the village of Saint-Rémy.\n\t Needless to say the painting is extremely popular even today with it being included in movies and tv shows.</string>
    <string name="title_3_10">The Starry Night</string>

    <string name="theory_3_11">Portrait of Dr. Gachet is one of the most revered paintings by the Dutch artist Vincent van Gogh. It depicts Dr. Paul Gachet who took care of Van Gogh during the final months of his life. There are two authenticated versions of the portrait, both painted in June 1890 at Auvers-sur-Oise. Both show Gachet sitting at a table and leaning his head on his right arm but they are easily differentiated in color and style. In 1990, the first version fetched a record price of $82.5 million.\n\tVan Gogh painted Gachet resting his right elbow on a red table, head in hand. Two yellow books as well as the purple medicinal herb foxglove are displayed on the table. The foxglove in the painting is a plant from which digitalis is extracted for the treatment of certain heart complaints, perhaps an attribute of Gachet as a physician.The doctor\'s \"sensitive face\", which Van Gogh wrote to Paul Gauguin carried \"the heartbroken expression of our time\".\n\tWith the Portrait of Dr. Gachet, Van Gogh sought to create a \"modern portrait\", which he wrote to his sister \"impassions me most—much, much more than all the rest of my métier.\"He also wrote, \"My self-portrait is done in nearly the same way but the blue is the fine blue of the Midi, and the clothes are a light lilac,\".</string>
    <string name="title_3_11">Dr. Gachet</string>

    <string name="title_activity_show_theory">showTheory</string>
    <string name="title_activity_renaissance_levels">renaissance_levels</string>
    <string name="title_activity_baroque_levels">baroque_levels</string>
    <string name="title_activity_impressionism_levels">impressionism_levels</string>
    <string name="title_activity_expressionism_levels">expressionism_levels</string>
    <string name="title_activity_cubism_levels">cubism_levels</string>
    <string name="title_activity_modern_levels">modern_levels</string>

</resources>
